<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on Jiheng Duan</title>
    <link>http://runawayfancy.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on Jiheng Duan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 02:53:19 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://runawayfancy.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum-Vitae</title>
      <link>http://runawayfancy.me/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 02:53:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://runawayfancy.me/cv/</guid>
      <description>You can download my curriculum-vitae via here. If the preview cannot be displayed, please refresh the page several times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, Redstone, and Editing</title>
      <link>http://runawayfancy.me/miscellany/redstone_tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 02:53:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://runawayfancy.me/miscellany/redstone_tech/</guid>
      <description>Redstone Tech Redstone is one of the most creative and sophisticated areas in Minecraft. Player used redstone objects like piston, repeater, observer combined with slime and honey block built up logical circuits and various machineries.
About Me My game ID is Runaway_Fancy.
6gt Roof Builder Chorus Flower Farm How to Use a Statistical Method to Analyze Random Tick in Minecraft and Its Application Our Redstone-tech Server I launched a survival multiple player (SMP) server focusing on redstone technology under game version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellany</title>
      <link>http://runawayfancy.me/miscellany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 02:53:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://runawayfancy.me/miscellany/</guid>
      <description>Seminar of Physics in UMThe seminar of Physics in the University of Macau was held by Yichen LUI and me in March, 2022. We aimed at enhancing the basic and advanced topics of fundamental physics and mathematics.Minecraft, Redstone and EditingI&#39;m a redstone technological Minecraft player focusing on mechanical design and game mechanism which are helpful in survival mode. Some showcase videos are edited for presentations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes and Presentations</title>
      <link>http://runawayfancy.me/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 02:53:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://runawayfancy.me/notes/</guid>
      <description>About I collected and summarized several notes from physics and mathematics courses during my undergraduate learning period. Most of them are referred to famous textbooks and lecture notes of online open courses. Unfortunately, most of the notes are handwritten and maybe I will rebuild them into $\LaTeX$ versions.
Selected topics Direct/Super exchange interaction and ISWAP gating SE-Interaction and ISWAP gate (Last Update 12/9/2022)
Displaced Fock State Displaced Fock State (Last Update 12/9/2022)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://runawayfancy.me/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 02:53:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://runawayfancy.me/research/</guid>
      <description>Quantum Physics A quantum algorithm for collision inducing disturbance vectors in SHA-1( arXiv:2210.12762 ) Advisor: Prof. Hou IAN
Oct. 2021 - Oct. 2022
Modern cryptographic protocols rely on sophisticated hash functions to generate quasi-unique numbers that serve as signatures for user authentication and other security verifications. The security could be compromised by finding texts hash-mappable to identical numbers, forming so-called collision attack. Seeding a disturbance vector in the hash mapping to obtain a successful collision is that a major focus of cryptography study in the past two decades to improve hash protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar on Physics at the University of Macau</title>
      <link>http://runawayfancy.me/miscellany/seminar_um/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 02:53:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://runawayfancy.me/miscellany/seminar_um/</guid>
      <description>About The seminar on physics at the University of Macau (SPUM), founded by Yichen Liu and Jiheng Duan, aims at improving the education of fundamental and advanced physics and mathematics. Students who have strong and wide knowledge in a specific area can admit to being a lecturer. Our organization is unofficial therefore we only invite students who have interests and talents in physics and mathematics study and research. Students are required to have a strong basis in calculus, linear algebra, and differential equations (ordinary and partial).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
