<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantum Computing | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/quantum-computing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/quantum-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Quantum Computing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu5de96a324c5fb1f54ea81865a52f325a_30207_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Quantum Computing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/quantum-computing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Flux Pulse Predistortion Methods</title>
      <link>https://example.com/research/predistortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/research/predistortion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flux tunable superconducting quantum interference devices (SQUID) are widely applied in today superconducting qubit architectures, e.g., flux qubit, tunable transmon, tunable coupler. The flux control requires sending flux pulses with desired waveform to bias the flux inside the SQUID loop. But many devices and imperfections can distort the waveform, inducing undesired flux fluctuations. Such waveform distortions will cause inaccurate frequency biasing or frequency damping, which leads to phase errors accumulation of a qubit (or coupler) and decrease the fidelity of qubit Z-control (e.g., iSWAP gate and CZ gate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distortions comes from many sources: &lt;strong&gt;analog filters&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., low-pass filter, high-pass filter), &lt;strong&gt;Bias-Tee&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AWG&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;junction points on the transmission line&lt;/strong&gt; (causing transmission and reflection of the EM wave), &lt;strong&gt;skin effect&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;on-chip resonance&lt;/strong&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim at exploring new techniques of combining reinforcement learning with digital inverse filtering methods (inverse IIR, and FIR filters), to effective and fast calibrate and fix the distortions. The predistortion method uses inversed digital filters, calibrated by the transient analysis of each components contributing distortions, to predistort the flux pulse inside the AWG, and all distortions can be countered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technique will be widely applied in future, and we are currently developing the inverse filter calibration code and the reinforcement learning model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Phase Controlled Qubit State Measurement Using Analog Microwave Phase Shifter</title>
      <link>https://example.com/research/phase_shifter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/research/phase_shifter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Superconducting quantum circuits are the most popular solid-state system used to implement quantum computation. Their computational units, the superconducting qubits, are micro-fabricated on substrates using thin-film deposition techniques similar to typical integrated circuits. The control and measurements of these qubits rely on waveguides microwave fields with techniques similar to those for millimeter-wave analog circuitry, where the output signal phase relative to the input plays a crucial role in determining the quantum state. A controllable phase to align the carrier and the amplitude envelope thus becomes essential. In this work, we implement a microwave phase shifter with 1 GHz bandwidth about the 4.75 GHz center frequency in conjunction with standard microwave equipment to measure a qubit.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-traditional-signal-modulation-and-phase-shifted-modulation-setup-shown-in-a-and-b-respectively-the-experimental-setup-design-layout-and-effective-circuit-of-the-phase-comparator-are-shown-in-this-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The traditional signal modulation and phase shifted modulation setup shown in (a) and (b), respectively. The experimental setup, design layout, and effective circuit of the phase comparator are shown in this figure.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/phase_shifter_hu5cd67629b6bb05df7f618747716ff656_664357_0334b40e87b38c6948403064ccfe04fc.webp 400w,
               /media/phase_shifter_hu5cd67629b6bb05df7f618747716ff656_664357_4a4da719a831298082d58a66c19c7844.webp 760w,
               /media/phase_shifter_hu5cd67629b6bb05df7f618747716ff656_664357_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/media/phase_shifter_hu5cd67629b6bb05df7f618747716ff656_664357_0334b40e87b38c6948403064ccfe04fc.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;621&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      The traditional signal modulation and phase shifted modulation setup shown in (a) and (b), respectively. The experimental setup, design layout, and effective circuit of the phase comparator are shown in this figure.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
